Justin Barnhill
200 Montclair Circle, Oxford, AL 36203
205-541-0846
justindbarnhill@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/justindbarnhill/

Summary

Aspiring devops engineer with over twenty years of industry experience interested in joining an organization leveraging technology in interesting ways, increasing my skillset, while using my past experience to offer unique perspectives on existing challenges.

Relevant Skills

Programming/Scripting: Experience with Python, Javascript, PowerShell, and other scripting languages in my current and previous roles automating various tasks to reduce redundant labor and deliver updated content to end user systems. I've utilized PHP, CSS, and various web markup languages both professionally and in personal projects for decades.

Cloud/Virtualization Technologies: Experienced with more virtualization technologies than I can list including Virtual PC, VMWare, Virtual Box, and Hyper-V; typically maintaining personal workspace or maintaining images for deployment to end users and developers. I'm experienced with Docker, GitHub, and other tools for code management. I've also been involved in migrating existing server based infrastructure supporting proprietary software packages to AWS for modernization projects with my current employer.

Database Technologies: I have direct work experience in multiple versions of Microsoft SQL in my current job role. I've also worked with lighter DB software in previous positions including MySQL and SQLite. I've used other DB tools in personal projects such as MongoDB, Amazon RDS, and Amazon DynamoDB.

Other: I've worked with every flavor of Microsoft operating systems starting with Windows 3.x, Apple's OS, various Linux / Unix systems, multiple ticketing systems (Remedy ARS, Jira, Zen desk), and remote access tools (VNC, RDP, Connectwise, Bomgar). I'm also very comfortable working with bash and other command line interfaces.

Work Experience

Sustaining Engineer, Idemia

October 2010 - present

Provide support and maintenance for a proprietary SQL based testing platform utilized for driver testing in approximately twenty four states and three foreign nations. Assist with debugging internal software to aid development in future improvements and upgrades. Identify potential training issues to be addressed by the proper personnel (either internal or client as contracts dictate). Support testing platform on multiple Windows based client machines and with all versions of SQL from 2000 to current along with AWS hosted environments. Utilize virtual environments for testing and troubleshooting. Develop internal maintenance procedures to streamline data integrity and automate proprietary software updates. Verify SLA is met in regards to initial contact, field level repairs, and contact with state managed helpdesk and internal helpdesk to insure corrective actions take place in a timely manner. Assist sales personnel in generating reports and statistics for case use scenarios and aid in client side demos during sales meetings. Design and develop integration components as needed to facilitate client environment communications with proprietary software.

Engineer, MTC Inc (now Aegis Factory)

July 2007 - October 2010

Troubleshoot any problems with a proprietary cash register system tailored for restaurants and small single location retail outlets in nine states throughout the southeast. Interface with development staff as needed concerning bugs and new feature testing and deployment. Coordinate new system rollout including configuring all hardware and software, delivery of equipment, wiring of site to supply connectivity, on site setup of hardware, testing and verification of hardware on site, and training of customer staff with both in house personnel and contractors. Assist with training staff to be self-sufficient team focused technicians working from home offices with little supervision including call escalation procedures, time management, professional phone etiquette, and service expectations. Audit trouble ticket closure reports, report to management, and develop strategies to make improvements. Foster

collaborative environment with other technicians to insure open communication environment. Meet with client side decision makers weekly to verify satisfaction, identify internal shortcomings, and develop plans to make corrections. Develop wiki resource for technicians to reference for common issues, develop workflows to address typical client reported issues, and develop printed manual for proprietary software products as needed.

Desktop Support Technician, Source Medical Solutions (now Surgical Information Systems) November 2005 - July 2007

Configure laptops and tablet PCs for use in demonstrating several proprietary healthcare software products deployed to surgical centers in over ten states. Troubleshoot any pc issues for internal staff as well as remote. Maintain inventory of all computer based assets. Assist in troubleshooting new revisions to proprietary software. Assist with training salespeople with new revisions for existing Source Medical Software products.

Senior Store Support Technician / Customer Service Representative, Books-A-Million / www.booksamillion.com August 2003 - November 2005

Build, repair, and maintain various computers and networking devices located within Books-A-Million's two hundred store chain. Support entire IT infrastructure at corporate headquarters as well as several satellite administrative facilities. Develop databases to track hardware inventory using Access. Assist with developing documentation regarding computerized cash register systems as part of a large scale Sarbanes-Oxley compliance program.

Technician, United States Postal Service (Teksystems/Dyncorp) - Contract September 1999 - April 2004

Build, repair, and maintain various computers and networking devices located in post offices around the state of Alabama. Perform various sys admin duties on the three hundred users LAN of the District Office. Address compatibility issues that arise between proprietary USPS software and commercial software and utilize very basic programming techniques to troubleshoot. Develop and maintain a database to track phone lines and hardware in several hundred locations within the Alabama district.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, Software Engineering, GPA 3.84 University of Phoenix , March 2009 – May 2011 Areas of study: general information technology, web development, and programming

Associate of Arts in Information Technology, GPA 3.87 Axia College of University of Phoenix , March 2007 - March 2009 Areas of study: general information technology

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner PCEP Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer

References

Hal Songer

205-908-1314 · hal.songer@us.idemia.com · Manager of Sustaining Engineering with Idemia

Brian Marvin

951-691-9062 · Owner MTC, Inc

Casey Phillips

205-503-3151 · caseyphillips@gmail.com · co-worker while contracting with MTC, Inc

Martin Fischer

205-936-3144 · martin@vinesauto.com · co-worker while employed with Books-A-Million

Andrew Morrow

678-787-3449 · beardedmongo@gmail.com · personal friend and full stack developer I've collaborated with on hobby projects